Tina Cai

UX/UI DESIGNER

CONTACT

Bay Area, CA, USA

(206) 407-4205

tinacai97.github.io/portfolio

(in) in/tinacai97

SKILLS

Research

Competitor analysis, user interviews, usability testing, user flows, user journeys, persona development, proof of concept creation

Design

Information architecture, sketching, wireframing, rapid prototyping, UI design, mobile design, web design, accessibile design

Software

Figma, PhotoShop, Illustrator, Mural, InVision, Marvel, Jira, VSCode, GitHub, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React

EDUCATION

Product Design Certificate

MAR 2022 - MAY 2022

Co.Lab, Cohort #10
Design Buddies Scholarship

User Experience Design Certificate

MAY 2021 - JAN 2022

CareerFoundry
Front-End Specialization

B.S. in Electrical & Computer Engineering

SEP 2015 - JUN 2019

University of Washington, Seattle Power Design Concentration

ABOUT

I am a UX/UI designer with experience in front-end development and engineering. I combine my newly-found creative and well-practiced analytical mindset to craft experiences with and for people. When not designing, find me playing video games, baking, or practicing pilates

EXPERIENCE

UX Design Specialist

JAN 2023 - PRESENT

SAP • AppHaus

- Simplified farm maintenance for Pif Paf Alimentos by designing a mobile solution that digitalized hard-to-track paper forms based on research data and SAP Build Apps capabilities
- Streamlined the adoption of SAP BTP for state tolling agencies by creating a reusable web-based proof of concept prototype of a vehicle tolling solution
- Increased visibility of SAP AppHaus both internally and externally by creating marketing proof points for the Pif Paf project that were used in SAP News and the international business event SAP Sapphire
- Expanded SAP AppHaus branding by assisting with the design of the "Design Timeline" to be constructed in the new AppHaus space

UX/UI Designer (Contract)

JUN 2022 - DEC 2022

Rowy

- Increased user sign up completion by 15% by re-designing the authentication, onboarding, and navigation process through product research and strict external constraints
- Prepared for monetization by designing the subscription, demo, and incoming paid features for both the Rowy product and website

Graduate Engineer

JAN 2020 - APR 2021

Arup

 Produced 100+ design deliverables across 13 unique customer projects by working closely with clients and engineering teams

Engineering Intern

JUN 2019 - SEP 2019

Katerra

 Helped deliver a design package of 80+ code compliant drawings for a multi-building apartment complex by cross-checking engineering designs based on building owner and team needs

PROJECTS

Mesh

MAR 2022 - MAY 2022

[tinacai.me/mesh.html]

- Worked alongside a product manager and developer to design a solution that empowers early-career tech talent to network
- Developed product HTML documentation and CSS styling to ensure proposed MVP shipped on time

Personal Design Portfolio [tinacai.me]

NOV 2021 - FEB 2022

 Designed and hand-developed an online portfolio to showcase design case studies and practice front-end development